Are you planning to eat out tonight or are you going to stay in to save the pennies?
你今晚打算出去吃饭，还是为了省钱在家做饭？
A meal out at a good restaurant or even a pizza parlour can set you back a small fortune, so cooking for yourself makes financial sense.
在一家不错的餐厅甚至披萨店吃一顿，都可能让你花掉一小笔钱，所以自己做饭从经济角度来说是明智的。
But with the rise in food prices, it's important to be a savvy shopper to keep your food bill in check.
但随着食品价格上涨，做个精明的购物者来控制食品开支就显得尤为重要。
These days our supermarket shelves are packed with a tempting array of food items: from the daily staples, like bread and milk, to the exotic, like mangoes and saffron.
如今，超市货架上摆满了琳琅满目的诱人食品：从面包、牛奶这类日常主食，到芒果、藏红花之类的异国风味食材，应有尽有。
There's also the option of buying ready meals – convenient food that comes at a price.
你也可以选择购买即食餐——这种食品虽然方便，但价格不菲。
However, if you're feeling the pinch, there are things you can do to make the money you spend on food go further.
不过，如果你手头拮据，还是有一些办法能让你花在食物上的钱更划算。
According to the BBC Food website, it's all about changing your habits.
据英国广播公司美食频道网站称，关键在于改变你的习惯。
It claims that cooking filling and tasty meals on a budget is easy.
该网站称，低成本做出既饱腹又美味的饭菜并非难事。
It suggests a number of 'tricks' such as using cheaper cuts of meat, "bulk out small amounts of meat with less expensive proteins" and "transform small amounts of leftovers into a filling meal".
网站还给出了不少“小窍门”，比如选用价格实惠的肉块、“用廉价蛋白质食材来搭配少量肉类做成一顿大餐”，以及“把少量剩菜剩饭做成一顿管饱的正餐”。
A favourite pastime of mine to help when money is tight is to stock up on items that are on special offer – such as BOGOF deals (Buy one, get one free).
当手头紧的时候，我最喜欢的娱乐消遣省钱活动就是囤购特价商品——比如“买一送一”的优惠活动。
However, this is more of a problem when it comes to perishable items like fresh fruit and vegetables.
但这种方法对于新鲜水果、蔬菜这类易腐烂食材来说，就不太适用了。
In the UK, about 39% of household food waste is fruit and veg.
在英国，约39%的家庭食物垃圾都是果蔬类。
So it's a good idea not to stock up on too much of these things.
所以，这类食材最好不要囤太多。
Store them carefully and make the most of them in all your recipes.
要妥善储存，并在各种食谱中充分利用它们。
Food waste is a big problem generally so shopping carefully can also reduce the amount we throw away.
食物浪费是一个普遍存在的大问题，因此谨慎购物也能减少我们丢弃的食物量。
And in Edinburgh in Scotland, it's possible to reduce waste and not break the bank by visiting a recycled food shop, which has been set up to prevent surplus food from shops ending up in the bin.
在苏格兰的爱丁堡，你可以光顾一家食品循环回收商店，既能减少浪费，又不会花太多钱。这家商店的设立是为了避免商店的过剩食品被扔进垃圾桶。
The Food Sharing Hub allows people to pay as much as they want for the rescued food, which is past its 'best before date'.
这家名为“食品共享中心”的商店允许人们想付多少就付多少来购买那些已过“最佳食用日期”的回收食品。
Of course, the biggest thing you can do to help your cash flow is to cut back on takeaway coffees and lunches.
当然，要改善资金状况，最有效的办法就是减少购买外卖咖啡和午餐的次数。
Making your own is usually healthier for you and your finances!
自己动手做，通常对你的健康和钱包都更有益！